Brian Zbriger

252 Skyiew Drive, Cromwell, CT 06416 Cell: (203) 810-0806 • brian.zbr@gmail.com

IT support professional for over 4 years, seeking to gain experience in software engineering with Python. Strong communication and research skills acquired through previous career as educator and sociologist.

Languages: Python – SQL – PowerShell – HTML – CSS

Certifications: Nucamp Back End, SQL, and DevOps with Python

(expected Nov. 2021)

CompTIA A+ (since Feb. 2017) – Network+ (since

Jan. 2018) – Security+ (since June 2018)

Operating Systems: Windows Desktop and Server – Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS)

General Applications: MS Office Suite (Outlook, Word, Excel, Powerpoint, etc.) –

Google Docs – Adobe Creative Suite – Web Browsers

(Chrome / Firefox / Edge / IE)

Ticketing Systems: ConnectWise – ServiceNow – HP Service Manager

Professional Experience

Cooperative Systems Windsor, CT 2019 - Present

Service Desk Technician II (Jan 2021 - Present) Service Desk Technician I (April 2019 - Dec 2020)

- Solving a wide range hardware, software and networking issues for end users at diverse clients, primarily remote.
- Automating Active Directory account creation and data management tasks with PowerShell scripting.
- Working with system engineers to support maintenance and administration of servers and network infrastructure.

Tek Systems / DXC / Pratt & Whitney

East Hartford, CT

2018-2019

Field Service Representative (Oct. 2018 – April 2019)

- Documenting customer communications and work logs through Service Now
- Diagnosing and repairing Dell laptops and desktops.
- Testing and troubleshooting monitors, docking stations and other peripherals
- Replacing system boards, RAM, hard drives and other components; reimaging devices as needed
- Troubleshooting software (mainly MS Office and web applications), Ethernet and WiFi network issues

IMACD Team Lead (Dec. 2017 – Oct. 2018) Desktop Configuration Technician (May 2017 – Dec. 2017)

- Deploying Apple and Lenovo laptops, and Lenovo desktops and thin clients to users
- Device refreshes and upgrades, including imaging and data transfers
- Troubleshooting standard applications (MS Office, Adobe Creative Suite and web applications) and network connectivity including Cisco AnyConnect VPN
- Communicating technical information to both technical and non-technical personnel
- Supervising special infrastructure projects in collaboration with project managers
- Serving as first point of escalation for difficult issues

Passion Analytics

Somerville, MA (remote)

2016 - 2017

Researcher / Web Content Developer (April 2016 – Feb. 2017)

- Developing interactive modules for an instructional website
- Researching and writing original, engaging content
- Implementing content using HTML via SurveyGizmo

Post University Waterbury, CT 2014-2017

Associate Faculty (Nov. 2014 – April 2017)

- Teaching online and classroom-based undergraduate courses
- Delivering content, managed grades and communicated with students via Blackboard
- Implementing online and multimedia content using HTML

Binghamton University

Vestal, NY

2007-2014

Adjunct Lecturer (Aug. 2010 – May 2014) Teaching Assistant (Aug. 2007 – May 2010)

- Received over \$50,000 in merit-based financial support, including a Fulbright research fellowship
- Designed and taught online and classroom-based undergraduate courses
- Delivered content, managed grades and communicated with students via Blackboard and implemented online and multimedia content using HTML

Education

- Binghamton University, PhD candidate in Sociology (GPA: 3.778)
- University of Massachusetts at Lowell, MA in Regional Economic and Social Development, graduated 2007 (GPA: 4.0)
- University of Massachusetts at Amherst, BA in Social Thought and Political Economy, graduated 2003 (GPA: 3.75)